var time = 15;
var intervalId;
var iQuestion = 0;
var ansKey;
var wins = 0;
var losses = 0;

// Initial object array of questions

var triviaQuestions = [ {question: "Bronze is an alloy consisting of two or more metals. What are they?", answer1: "Copper and zinc" , answer2: "Copper and tin", answer3: "Copper and gold" , answer4:"Copper and lead" , answerKey: "2"}, 
                        {question: "What colour is Cerulean?" , answer1: "Red" , answer2: "Green", answer3: "yellow" , answer4:"Blue" , answerKey: "4"}, 
                        {question: "What type of electrical charge does a neutron have?", answer1: "Negative" , answer2: "Positive", answer3: "No charge" , answer4:"Double negative" , answerKey: "3"}, 
                        {question: "The first sheep was successfully cloned in 1996, what was the sheepâ€™s name?" , answer1: "Dolly" , answer2: "Donna", answer3: "Holly" , answer4:"Hailey" , answerKey: "1"}, 
                        {question: "Mycology is the study of:" , answer1: "Insects" , answer2: "Water bodies", answer3: "Fungi" , answer4:"Volcanos" , answerKey: "3"}, 
                        {question: "Air is mostly made up of:" , answer1: "Oxygen" , answer2: "Nitrogen ", answer3: "Carbon dioxide" , answer4:"Argon" , answerKey: "2"}, 
                        {question: "What is the first element on the periodic table?" , answer1: "Sodium" , answer2: "Oxygen", answer3: "Helium" , answer4:"Hydrogen" , answerKey: "4"}, 
                        {question: "Which side of your brain has more neurons?" , answer1: "Right" , answer2: "Left", answer3: "Both the same" , answer4:"None of the above" , answerKey: "2"}, 
                        {question: "Which Desert dominates a large area of Northern Africa?" , answer1: "Kalahari" , answer2: "Sahara", answer3: "Gobi" , answer4:"Atacama" , answerKey: "2"}, 
                        {question: "What is the body of water that borders Greece, Turkey and Southern Italy?" , answer1: "Red Sea" , answer2: "Black Sea", answer3: "Aegean Sea" , answer4:"Mediterranean Sea" , answerKey: "3"}, 
                        ];

window.onload = function() {
    //startTimer();
    // $("#start").on("click", startTimer);
    // $("#stop").on("click", stop);
    // $("#reset").on("click", reset);
    // $("#start").on("click", start);
  };

function startTimer(){
    intervalId = setInterval(count, 1000);
}

function count(){
    $("#timeLeft").text("Time Remaining: " + time + " Seconds");
    time--;
    if (time == 0)
    {
        clearInterval(intervalId);
        losses++;
        nextQuestion();         
    }
    
}

function nextQuestion()
{    
    $("#losses").text("Total losses: " + losses);
    $("#wins").text("Total Wins: " + wins);
    $("#btnStart").attr("hidden", "true");
          
    if(iQuestion < triviaQuestions.length)
    {
        //$("#amIcorrect").text("");    
        time = 15;
        startTimer();
        $("#question").text(triviaQuestions[iQuestion].question);
        $("#answer1").text(triviaQuestions[iQuestion].answer1);
        $("#answer2").text(triviaQuestions[iQuestion].answer2);
        $("#answer3").text(triviaQuestions[iQuestion].answer3);
        $("#answer4").text(triviaQuestions[iQuestion].answer4);
        ansKey = "answer" + triviaQuestions[iQuestion].answerKey;
        var answer = $(ansKey);
        answer.attr("data-name", "correct");
        console.log("The answerKey is " + ansKey);
        iQuestion ++;
    }
    else
    {
        clearInterval(intervalId);
        time = 0;
        $("#timeLeft").text("Time Remaining: " + time + " Seconds");
        //show the wins and losses
        $("#question").text("Here is your score!");
        $("#btnStart").attr("hidden", "true");
        $(".answer").attr("hidden","true");
    }
}

$(".answer").on("click", function(){
    
    if(time != 0)
    {
        var answerId = $(this).attr("id");
        // console.log("ans clicked : " + answerId);
        // console.log(ansKey);
        clearInterval(intervalId);
        // time = 0;
        if (answerId == ansKey)
        {       
            wins++;
            console.log("No of wins: " + wins);       
            //play sound
            // console.log("play sound here"); 
            // $('#bellSound')[0].play();        
            $("#wins").text("Total Wins: " + wins);  
        }
        else
        {        
            losses++;
            console.log("No of losses: " + losses);       
            $("#losses").text("Total losses: " + losses);    
        }            
        nextQuestion();
    }    
})